Brandon Pohl

Englewood, Colorado 80113 | (561) 703-4900 | brandonpohl01@gmail.com

SUMMARY

An accomplished and resourceful software development manager with comprehensive technical expertise in system design, development, and integration, quality control, IT security, and technical writing. Proven capabilities in keeping concurrent projects on task in high-volume settings, utilizing advanced features to boost the efficiency of large-scale networks, ensuring resources and other assets are available to team members and leadership, and successfully representing companies at industry events. A top-performing leader who is committed to achieving profitability and success with an organization.

TECHNICAL SKILLSET

Frameworks: Dotnet Core, Angular

<u>Languages</u>: C#, SQL, Typescript, JQuery, HTML, SCSS, YAML <u>Tools</u>: AWS, SQL Server, Postgres, Octopus, Azure Dev Ops

Additional Skills: IIS, Visio, MSMQ, REST

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Team Lead, Advisor – 2020-2024

TransUnion LLC - Greenwood Village, Colorado

- Enforced code quality, information security, and performance standards at scale for all projects within team's purview.
- Oversaw the re-hosting of vital project onto AWS cloud, harnessing advanced features to enhance reliability, efficiency, and costeffectiveness.
- Led and provided technical guidance across multiple teams, projects, and feature deliveries.
- Contributed to the design and architecture of systems that supported over six million transactions per minute.
- Managed workload and deliverables of two development teams, ensuring timely project deliveries.
- Oversaw the CI/CD pipelines using Azure Dev Ops and Octopus for 30+ services and projects.
- Reviewed API integration documents and designed workflow diagrams to guide team planning efforts.
- Regularly participated and lectured in the company architecture and .Net Center of Excellence groups.
- Founded and hosted company's local Angular Meetup Group.

Senior Software Developer – 2013-2021

TransUnion LLC - Greenwood Village, Colorado

Dotnet

- Developed and delivered 5 greenfield projects using dotnet core and Angular.
- Designed and implemented RESTful services using dotnet core and dotnet 4.
- Improved performance and accuracy of a critical service that was the backbone of all products at TURSS.
- Created a common microservice layer used by independent verticals for 90% of their business logic.
- Implemented dependency injection for dotnet applications using StructureMap, Unity, and dotnet core's built in api.
- Refactored applications into three-tiered architecture with a presentation, business, and data layers.
- Championed the use of NuGet package manager for more reliable dll referencing.

Angular

- Architected and built six Angular websites, delivering them on schedule within 2 years.
- Led implementation of Angular, ngrx, yarn, dotnet core, and Moq as company standards.
- Created common Angular libraries for use across all websites, promoting code reuse and consistency.
- Implemented variety of services, including webpage timeout, session, scrolling to elements, and API integrations.
- Developed all validators for both template and Reactive forms.
- Designed error and request handling using HttpInterceptor.
- Integrated with third-party tracking tools such as Google Tag Manager, Optimizely, and Mixpanel.
- Implemented lazy loading modules and upgraded Angular from v2 to v12.
- Attended in-person Angular talk lead by Google engineers at company facilities in Chicago.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Developer - 2012-2013

Restaurant Solutions Inc - Denver, Colorado

- Rolled out greenfield .Net 4.0 product for streamlined payroll processing administration.
- Improved system performance using SQL Server, OO design patterns, priority queues, and algorithm efficiency.
- Built token-based security for a Web Service based API.
- Automated complex payroll tax calculation and payment tasks.
- Reengineered views and workflows for improved efficiency, resulting in significant performance improvements.
- Implemented up-to-date development methodologies and technologies to reduce feature implementation times.
- Configured, customized, and managed TFS 2010 workflows and builds.

Snr. Software Integration Engineer, System Innovators

Jacksonville, Florida — 5+ Years (2007-2012)

- Developed a cross-platform shopping cart implementation using PHP, JSON, JavaScript, C#, and .Net web services.
- Used agile development and C# to deliver custom interfaces to a variety of back-end systems, including Oracle, Microsoft SQL Server, Web Services, Flat Files, FTP, DB2, and ODBC.
- Created a custom API using .net 2.0 Web Services and SQL stored procedures for rapid record importing.
- Indexed and tuned SQL Server databases for optimized performance using execution plans and SQL Performance Monitors.
- Resolved a wide range of bugs within our customer specific C# and C++ integrations.
- Tested the application and tracked bug progress for high priority clients.
- Wrote user interface automation test to ensure the quality of our product.

EDUCATION

University of North Florida

Jacksonville, Florida — 2004-2009

- ✓ Bachelor's of Science in Computer Science
- ✓ Minor in Mathematical Science